Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986 | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue Web Design Portfolio: https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Chemist, full-stack web developer, and property manager. Education in full-stack development and Ph.D. in chemistry both from UCLA. Experienced independent researcher, business manager, scientist, and problem solver. Values include community, ethics, integrity, and business sense. Leadership, teamwork, and public speaking skills stem from years spent as a classroom teacher and a group fitness leader. Top aim is to find success in life and improve the lives of others.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Knowledge of the importance lab safety gained through years of chemical laboratory experience
- Skill with swiftly diving into scientific research, literature, and learning
- Experience with a variety of common lab techniques such as NMR and IR spectroscopy, cyclic voltammetry, Schlenk and glovebox work, titration, synthesis, crystallization, distillation, purification
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, mobileresponsive web design, version control with Git, code testing with tools such as Postman and Jest
- JavaScript/HTML/CSS as main coding languages
- Python and C/C++ as secondary languages, with ability and skill to learn further languages
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js)
- Use of established libraries such as Redux, ¡Query, Flask, Sass, Bootstrap, TypeScript
- SQL database work, as well as non-relational database management with MongoDB or Firebase
- AJAX calls for integrating APIs

EMPLOYMENT

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - Current

- Worked independently on Python programs to streamline workflow
- Applied knowledge of repair skills to improve value of multiple properties, saving thousands of dollars on outside contractor hires
- Rigorous documentation of construction projects and account tracking benefitted bottom line
- Managed over a dozen buildings while responsible for business decisions on properties worth millions
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Independent Chemistry Tutor:

• Praised for making a "night and day" difference by helping high school students learn chemistry, improve grades, and appreciate science

Aim-Hi Global, LLC. https://aimhiglobal.com

December 2020 - May 2020

Web Development Intern

- Performed team coding duties such as code review, documentation, and website deployment
- Implemented user settings, added routing functionality, refactored code, designed interactive calendar, used social media APIs, and improved documentation, while using React and Firebase

Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - December 2014

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award and two separate fellowships
- Close supervision of hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

Chromadex, Inc.:

June 2006 - June 2007

Associate inventory manager

• Handled chemical inventory and improved organization for botanical reference standards company

EDUCATION

Computer Science Associate Degree - Santa Monica College

CS50 Computer Science Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online
Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension

Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles

September 2007 - December 2014

B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine

September 2003 - July 2007

PUBLICATIONS

Reactions of group III biheterocyclic complexes. Carver, C. T.; Benitez, D.; Miller, K. L.; Williams, B. N.; Tkatchouk, E.; Goddard, W. A.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *J. Am. Chem. Soc.* **2009**, *131*, 10269-10278.

Dearomatization reactions of N-heterocycles mediated by group III complexes. Miller, K. L.; Williams, B. N.; Benitez, D.; Carver, C. T.; Ogilby, K. R.; Tkatchouk, E.; Goddard III, W. A.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *J. Am. Chem. Soc.* **2010**, *132*, 342-355.

Reactions of aromatic N-heterocycles with a lutetium benzyl complex supported by a ferrocene-diamide ligand. Wong, A. W.; Miller, K. L.; Diaconescu, P. L.; Dalton Trans. 2010, 39, 6726-6731.

Reactions of imidazoles with electrophilic metal alkyl complexes. Miller, K. L.; Williams, B. N.; Carver, C. T.; Diaconescu, P. L.; Organometallics 2010, 29, 2272-2281.

Group 3 metal complexes of radical-anionic 2,2'-bipyridyl ligands. Williams, B. N.; Huang, W.; Miller, K. L.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *Inorg. Chem.* 2010, 49, 11493-11498.

An unusual hydrogen migration/C-H activation reaction with group 3 metals. Williams, B. N.; Benitez, D.; Miller, K. L.; Tkatchouk, E.; Goddard, W. A.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *J. Am. Chem. Soc.* **2011**, *133*, 4680-4683.

Synthesis of symmetrically and unsymmetrically 3,5-dimethylbenzyl-substituted 1,1'-ferrocene diamines. Lee, J. A.; Williams, B. N.; Ogilby, K. R.; Miller, K. L.; Diaconescu, P. L.; *J. Organomet. Chem.* 2011, 696, 4090-4094.

Unique Properties and Reactivity of Electrophilic Metal Centers Supported by Ferrocene Diamide Ligands. Miller, K. L.; UCLA 2014.